These characters have no scripted dialogue.
They talk, remember and change plans in real time —
driven by AI running on my own laptop.
Ordinary game NPCs repeat the same lines on a loop.
Here, every villager has memory,
a personality, and an agenda of their own.
A reimagining of Stanford's Generative Agents —
but fully offline, on an RTX 4060.
I tell just one villager there's a party
at the plaza tonight.
No one else.
And then word starts to spread.
Diego hears it from Maria,
and passes it on to Sofia.
Sofia tells Carlos.
Nobody coded that chain —
it emerges from their conversations.
By evening, the ones who heard
show up at the plaza — right on time.
Five of five knew it;
four learned it by word of mouth.
Under the hood: a Python brain —
memory, relevance-based retrieval,
reflection, and planning.
It talks to Unity over WebSocket,
turn-based so a single GPU can run it.
No cloud. No APIs. No per-token cost.
Just my GPU — and a village that comes alive.